Thales from the city of Miletos in present Turkey (at that time belonging to Greece)
is usually considered the first Western philosopher.
This means that he wanted to find an alternative to the prevailing mythological explanation for the origin of everything.
Like many other natural philosophers, Thales was mainly employed by the question of what kind of material the world consisted of.
He searched for the origin of everything, a common building block or a watch - something he called Arche.
His response came to be 'water' because he could see that water at very low temperature
Was hard as stone (ice) and at high temperatures like air (steam).
When it was raining, plants penetrated from the soil, something he interpreted as being water in some form.
Everything living needed a large and constant intake of water to continue to live.
In addition, he must have been the person who introduced mathematics in Greece, something he must have learned in Egypt.
He has also contributed his own discoveries in the subject, mainly through what we today feel like Thales theorem
- That the strip angle to a semi -circle is always 90 °.
Unfortunately, none of Thale's writings are preserved (he must have written two philosophical works),
Without everything we know about him comes from other historical renovations.
He must have died at the age of 78, exhausted by heat, age and thirst, as a spectator during the 58th Olympiad in Athens.